A Guide to the Papers of the Janney and Related Gilmour and Pollock Families 1695(1755-1944)1981
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence and Papers of the Gilmour, Janney, and Pollock Families
  - Letters to Abraham David Pollock Gilmour and Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from family 1899-1944, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Letters to Abraham David Pollock Gilmour and Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1935 (Box 3)
    re their marriage
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1908-1934, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1935 Jan, 4 folders (Box 3)
    re her engagement
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1935 Feb-Dec, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1936-1965, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from John Janney, Jr. 1929-1964 (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Lilias Janney 1908-1929 (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Lilias Janney 1935, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Lilias Janney 1936-1940, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Lilias Janney n.d., 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Lucy (Stevenson) Janney 1929-1938 (Box 4)
  - Letters to Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour from Thomas Gordon Janney 1929-1944, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of Abraham David Pollock Gilmour and Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1934-1941, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Papers of Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1922-1943 (Box 4)
    re Garden Clubs
  - Letters to Abram David Pollock Janney and Lucy (Stevenson) Janney 1898-1946 (Box 5)
  - Letters from Charles Phillips Janney 1870-1923 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Charles Phillips Janney and Nannie Lee (Pollock) Janney 1865-1923 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Charles Phillips Janney from William Edward Dodd, and related 1912-1925 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Charles Phillips Janney from Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1916-1924 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Charles Phillips Janney from Lilias Janney 1908, 1916 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Charles Phillips Janney from Nannie Lee (Pollock) Janney 1907-1908, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Letters to Nannie Lee (Pollock) Janney from Charles Phillips Janney 1868-1869, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Papers of Charles Phillips Janney 1852-1922 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence of John Janney, Jr. 1896-1899 (Box 5)
  - Political Papers of John Janney, Jr. 1932, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney 1915-1951 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney from "Bessie" 1920 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney from family 1913-1936, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney from Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1918-1937, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney from Thomas Gordon Janney 1921-1944 (Box 5)
  - Letters to Lilias Janney and Nancy Lee Janney 1923-1935 (Box 5)
  - Letters from Nathaniel E. Janney to James C. Janney 1834-1848 (Box 6)
  - Letters from Nathaniel E. Janney to Mary Janney 1837-1840 (Box 6)
  - Letters to Thomas Gordon Janney 1886-1920 (Box 6)
  - Letters to Lily Pollock 1908-1910, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Financial and Legal Papers of the Janney familiy and others 1696(1755-1873)1906 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence of the Janney and Pollock families 1858-1944, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Address Book kept by Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour ca. 1941-1958, Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Business Woman's Circle Meetings Minutes kept by Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1939-1940, Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Gunston Hall Address Book kept by Nancy Lee Janney, along with a brochure 1903-1904, n.d., Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Gunston Hall "Memoir Book" kept by Nancy Lee Janney 1903-1904, Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Memorandum Book kept by Charles Phillips Janney 1860, Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Photograph Album kept by Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1900-1925, Loose photographs removed from oversize photograph album (Box 8)
  - Travel Joural to Europe and Bermuda kept by Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1928-1955, Bound volume (Box 8)
  - Travel Journals to Japan and China kept by Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour 1918, 2 bound volumes (Box 8)
  - Photograph Album kept by Nancy Lee Gilmour ca. 1900-1905 (Oversize P-22)
  - Passport for A[braham] D[avid] P[ollock] Gilmour 1913 May 5 (Oversize M-22)
- Papers re the Gilmour, Janney, and Pollack families
  - Genealogical data on the Janney and Pollock families 1888-1938 (Box 6)
  - Genealogical data on the Janney family 1825-1966, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Genealogical data on the Janney family 1904, 1939, Printed (Box 6)
  - Genealogical data on the Janney family compiled by Melvin Lee Steadman, Jr. 1967-1968, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Historical data on Loudoun County, Virginia and related 1879-1958, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1873-1953, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Organizational Papers 1907-1960 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Abraham David Pollock Gilmour and Nancy Lee (Janney) Gilmour ca. 1884-1950 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Abraham David Pollock Janney ca. 1885, 1900-1901 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Charles Phillips Janney and Nannie Lee (Pollock) Janney 1868 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Charles Phillips Janney and family 1879-1931, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Lilias Janney ca. 1876-1896 (Box 7)
  - Photographs of Robert Stevenson Janney 1916-1943, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Photographs of the Janney and Pollock family members and others ca. 1887-1958, n.d., 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Photographs of the Janney and Pollock family members: Potraits ca. 1880-1897, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Photographs of the Janney and Pollack family members and servants ca. 1863-1878, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Photographs of Leesburg and Loudoun County Residences ca. 1890-1957, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Religious and Church-related Material 1928-1944, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Travel Brochures and other Papers 1917-1929, n.d. (Box 7)
    re travel in Eurasia and the United States
  - Travel Brochures and other Papers 1928-1936 (Box 7)
    re travel in the United Kingdom
  - Scrapbook 1943-1949, Bound volume; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Framed Photograph of Major Robert Stevenson Janney of the United States Army Air Force 1943 (Oversize R-11)